I'll start who...this while thank you very much for calming
we have the clicker with the click ago...time...the clicker have to
...somewhere click is broken?
...have to...something I hope not.
Welcome to the session of going mobile with csharp with the visual studio and...
Well, this is not me...inserted for us all right this is I'll they
cast them the chief technical officer for examining and I'm james month...developer
of angeles examine been doing dot net for all not as long as you miguel
now not quite I got there ten years maybe a little bit before gummy and a little
bit via right...you guys...no is that I am actually crashing
...session I don't know what happened I was busy I don't know what happened but james was
...that build and at the last-minute two weeks ago joseph
...mean to doing the presentation...and,
I figured fear would do something fun this time around so, we're
...talk about that now of course before we can we can get the fun part
which should give some background for those of you that the know what,... the want to get some of the
context so when the today we're going to show you now built end-to-end it was a very
...it took us two weeks to build two weeks we finished last
night and out maybe a little bit this morning at two am ...a
...when nicholas friday...perfect gotten...and honestly,
honestly it was finish limit earlier but...testing the app we ended up consuming
all over free asher credits so we have...the last night figure out how to move it out from my personal
account...some...yeah, so, post-production we didn't really think this through
what anyways...about that today so...talk a lot about the same...platform and this is
where designing developing and integrating are love and passion for csharp and dot
net across ios android...all the windows platforms as well and,
we focus a lot and this is this were in visual studio using
...designers using our favorite libraries and explore all this as well as there is actually a lot more than
...the gal talked about that we're going to show you everything in our platform last time
egl came and spoke at build we had a...just launching for the first-time
...some brand-new exciting things since last build for instance it's not just about
designing developing application about test
abilities wow that's where the zimmer new...tasks zimmer task cloud come in
you build automated csharp scripts or really scripts the tester ios
...android applications with...was amr or not we
also think also what happens after you ship your application what happens when this free
...credits go down up and make sure that you can monitor application for
...analytics but also crash reporting and focus on
...insights for any of your applications
...windows ios android but also I point out that we actually did usability
testing was a short period compress creative usability testing but we learn a couple of interesting
less yes, we'll talk about that later and we have
...amazing platform to learn all this as well which I'll talk about the...university with live interactive
instructor so this is...your complete mobile...anything you want to do in mobile.
I think examine why iphone over the for year-ago four years ago when I moved to seattle
to take a job is the solow mobile developers small
...they tell me hey you got to...back
then that two weeks to build and ios android...windows phone an windows store application and demo
at cs said okay...to two-month plenty of time
...doing that two weeks because able to build-up my shared csharp back-end everything a lot
...view models sequel databases wrestle service calls and
...beautiful user interface for ios android and
of course windows but this application we built now done a lot of things that
...game programming printer software.
Because everyone's got...right printer software for about four years right so the idea that...expert today and we'll get into the idea
...actually contained heavy dose of server a work not only
a heavy does of server work but a lot of interesting problems that we're not familiar with
...the project two weeks ago I mean we...the articles
and url this stuff on the internet's but you don't really know what you're doing until you're doing so
what was interesting this time around is not only that we shared it csharp
lodging between the ui but also we ended up sharing a bunch of code
with the server right and right now I runs and asher...we're hoping to put...also on one
...running and of course...running linux we end up actually sharing code between
the client-server and have some data their has the first-time I ever did...I was amaze just has a
...library boom just shared because we tend to be client people we
...and this time around to pull them up together we had
to do end-to-end so we learn entity framework ...
jobs we use send grid we used service...service...because this is web scale
...up push notifications for google klout messing adrg notification
...in really tying entire you check boxes down it's like all
the services to bring a great story together not only was fun but also give me an excuse to
...every meeting from my boss...I had I got to get more meetings the right so
this is roughly what we explained last year you share csharp code but,
you have these...pieces of code that are specific to each platform you get
some idea specific go to have abolished experience and idealize abolish experience
and android abolished experience on windows each are now some of you
...not necessarily need every bit of polish last year when should...can...the next
...wimp...an api
cause I'm informs which is an api that essentially gives you a way of describing the
...a high-level enable wrong
with native controls on every platform and, what we build can
...put this together two days we don't have time to show today but
we did also build a companion administration up for...what we're going to...today and it's
hundred-percent code sharing now I said csharp everywhere but the reality
is that everything that you can do that csharp you can also we would have...I'm a big of...fan but,
it's often difficult to put in
...I want-to make sure you guys now you can use both of them?
And, the way that we're doing this for those of you that are not familiar it's
...developer you're familiar with all these namespaces and all
these api that exists here right up and there's a class of
api is the boxing blue that are you why specific api
...particular are windows api for the new platform but, in the past was windows forms
...was wpf or maybe even a speedup net but these are presentation layer api
zer operating systems specific
api so the way that you have to think about how to build applications for andrea now
us everything in...something that you can...works everywhere or everything that you can get
enough people new jay and, when you go to...essentially have to use a different set of
api what is essentially the same thing you have to learn a new model for the ui a new
model for notifications and things like that and the same thing it's repeated again with
android but essentially now you can think you can immediately see how you could structure and application
to be cross-platform how you structure...code to work in this way how do I switch
the next one which one is just right...
So, what is important approach...taking is that we're projecting the android...the ios
api or the macape as we're really talked much about it but we project all of these
api into csharp so you can consume the same set everything that you could
...some from swift objectives your java you can consumes from csharp so you're never at
...disadvantage if you want to learn how to build an application from the ground-up
using this model and also get one of the school csharp shirts the gentleman here
in the front is using or there was a gentleman with the
...somewhere a nice...red and yellow I
...you can download this application...when you download the
application and run it you can actuallyget the shirt...get an idea of how it structured?
So, this is how it started.
At two weeks ago ...I'm going to...onstage and I said
...app ideas are the conversations lab.
And, now the problem is that it's a crowded space.
Right so we're going to build...map we don't want...to be a throw-away apple
...this to be an application that will sustain ...this but that's
the time the test of time,... something that I...open up every single-day and use want to create a real-time
communication application that was fun in new will be
an amazing demo but also something that we can actually put out there but like
...goss a huge...space we are multiple...plant check klein's on our
phones already has all these different services are doing different things and that was something that
...can we do different right so what we do
well luckily for us hbo just published silicon valley
...first full season and hbo now on the daily baconthat we can load it
up we bench watch the can valley and we have...we actually came up with
a couple of lessons how to build successful startups so we're going to share experience with you guys.
Measure experience what and all of this who
...binge watching come up with this plan execute
deliver them onstage...and we tested and we...hit and we
did usability testing so here are the parameters and this is what we learn from
the silicon valley so we learn a lot of lessons I want to...those with you so you can go back home
...your companies so first thing...want to find a large market and, you know,
often work focus...maybe we can, you know,
maybe we can sell groceries or maybe we can get you know,
people into...but...a lot of work might take a pick-up
...and filter it and...the filter app it's done...on thing so,
we...this idea there's seventy eight million children in america it's
...untapped market there's one...billion.
Children in the world.
This is a big-market in fact I think that when...and...we're going to get windows in
...billion devices is not thinking big enough that
...get three years... you big also what...this information from wikipedia.
It...it's an all-time high right now is
...all downtime high so this is the perfect time to get into the market
...with a grain of salt we don't really know if it's an...other wikipedia that if you
...wikipedia notes for this is the key.
For every child there's
...average one-point-eight concerned parents very concerned parents this is a big-market
guys this is a huge market talk about six million people so
...we're going-to go after that large market second we need to find
the differentiator how is the from what's up from facebook
a messenger from all of this stuff that it's out there, you know,
everyone has their features we're
defying something important so we find something that was important to us which is
...so our messaging application is focused...
...father andparent and, you know, ever since I had kids iso to
freak out like the character of the simpson where she ask is anybody going to think of the children
galloping...exactly and
then we define a product market fit bright...again silicon valley
...you need to find something that the market demands and why do we figured out is that
well there's all kinds of parenting styles right panting is a little bit like
...rails...opinionated sub-set of principles right
soyou might not necessarily thank you?
Cminor necessarily agree.
With all the principles...work in a built and app that is focused on a particular
set of parents and if that's ten percent of twenty percent that's still a lot of percent
...a billion people so.
All I get a do...is target that demographic
and the demographic that were targeting is the helicopter parenting demographic these are parents
dot want to constantly...monitor what's happening with their kids that want the
...make sure that they grow up as responsible adults...want to have a happy childhood so,
that's our target market reallythat's what we're doing and then we need to find a way of
growing or market to make this thing goes viral and to make think people user application so,
we're going to use the best industry practices that exist today we're going to gamy
...parenting we're going to do it through three vectors we're going to use points.
The children can earn and they can exchange for things like sleep overs play...yeah,
I mean you can be and games whatever you want to disneyland who
...that's the ultimate reward...a learn one thing is that budgets are the key to everything so we're going to give them
budgets exchanges points also for badges and stickers and things like that
right and also I think I'm a guy with social responsibility volume twitter I
...always have the social land do everything that I do and,
we want to use this up to bring could to the world
right so we're going to shame parents into becoming better parents the idea is
...you make it to the top of the list right there I mean I have a friend
that is always competing with these other parents like all they just got these...them they just got the dog and,
you know, so, kids are going to have a chance to read their parents right?
they're going to have to a chance to basically say hey that just not happening for me what you know,...
So, we're going to use all of this properties do essentially.
You know, hope for a better world.
So, let me introduce replication...is called
can chat it's a chat application focus on the children and,
now james is going to show we're going to show this on the emulator we have a running
...devices but to project is going to...going to work better we showed in the...is all want to...
...talk about the will so the real part of it and get into the demo...which
It was get up and running...it's kind of walk through what's going
...here we have...ios six simulator on the left-hand side and we hammers
ameri android player with lollipops here cisco...and...these up.
So, when you start the
...to pick a favorite color of lower-paying currently other themes that you may have?
And, here we can see we have a list of the bottom...
chats are friends that are on here beautiful material design back and forth
and we can add pingback and for...wonder is to...is we actually were actually using the
...material design from google it looks pretty gorgeous the...the refresh is
...put a lot of nice...and each one of these is a native up on each platform so,
we see joseph here in the parallels
you this first let's go ahead and have a little chat hereI'm ready I'm ready?
Earlier is live-in might kinder chat thing sell.
All right.
He's...but you're probably better off talking to joseph.
M talking myself now that's no fun this is samoa the...that have a ton
...what let's go ahead and add let-me abigail so we're going to my friends tab here
...from my contact lists and there's miguel.
...the worked.
Perhaps.
Help...things are things are...okay there we
go from yahoo adam to our contacts
and added there you are little sideways...message.
All right so there we see so now I'm multiple
chat conversations going back and forth...you this guy and I am I am joey south dog.
Subbed odg is a new way of saying dog and topic...boom.
...comes right...
Back and forth now one of the one thing the entire bike so now you're thinking well how is different seems like a
chat application it seems like a channel applications what is unique about this right
I could talk about how we scale this thing we actually hope that this is going to scale big
times because everybody on silicon valley knows ...web scale right,
...so, we pick taj are we...entity framework for the database we have
a rest endpoint that actually manages everything that has to do with
france collections of friends so on and then we is
websites the socket service workers to actually do the life messes exchange we have
...symbol you can also get a little bubble when you're typing so we're going to have that feature so
experience is great but what makes this unique and what makes is
special is that we're really concerned about privacy we live in a world where
security...a top concern it's a top concern for parents and you know,
what's up actually launch without any cryptography at all they were just
...plain-text messages not only resenting plain-text messages and you could intercept them but you could
also inject them they were susceptible to manage the middle attacks so we wanted to have
something that was a hundred-percent secure so what algebra vid the
lot-of facilities for actually managing identity's for...we created our own identity
system with a couple of design principles first every time I send a message
to james I'm using his public key to encrypt the message so all I
have...his public key I...the message and I send it to him also
thank you this is an app infertility right so we didn't want children to
...passwords or have a password manager
...complicated so the way that you can sign up...with the magnet
and actually sign up for the service...multiple devices just using that his email address or a
...to confirm his identity so essentially you can have a phone...android you know,
why...on anything you want and they're only together and there's never a public
...that's what we had to build our own identity system so
build identity system but most importantly I think that the key and
...see this the key for helicopter parenting really is being able to monitor
the communications of your children so what you do is when you click this little link bottom you
can link to apparent email address the first-time and when you
do that what would do is we integrate the public key of the
...into the identity so every time that you send a message
to james' that are mom gets a
message and this is all built in the principle that if you have nothing to fear if
you have nothing to hide and you have nothing to fear and?
...want the at the breeder culture where people are ok sharing this information
with their parents now you might be thinking as a kid well
...one mom or dad to know what I'm...so this is what the gamification peace
...and plight social we have so far right now we're doing the more you use the app the
more points you aren't so essentially you're trying if you're trying to escape the system by
going-to facebook messenger you're not going to get those points are not going
to get that sleep over you're not going to get that toward that you want so if you want to the points you
...spate kinder chat second thing also we integrated
system where you actually get you get to claim the things that you've done I struggle with my daughter
...broccoli she does not...there's no way of getting broccoliso,
...my daughter...broccoli exactly so when you're on here
...your child and can then say I like to approve a task then get points for this that you
...then later on as a parent which is really...appending...I can considering click
...keep, you know, brushing my teeth and get points as a poinsettia pending currently in the system
right another...what I can do is like is...can come to my apple...for example,
if you get click and finish homework...just got my I'll watch I'll watch
...my app and then I can I can both monitor
the conversations right or I can approve tasks and these guys I could approve, yeah,
it looks like he finish the homework but...said I the broccoli
...think so...so what this is the way this is one of the
components of the gamification that we're going to introduce into the into the app additionally
...we haven't so when you can you can selector different avatar or for instance you can come
in...a photo from the gallery take a photo so maybe one hips...caddo over...
...upload the photo to the server implode back down to the same thing's true
over jan android you...pick from the...great native features but experience
...actually identity and your friends you...is that really...that makes over
there like actually doing this so the gamification ties...not only just my doing
...actually using the application on a databases so that's the central notificationnow
was a kid I was a huge video game generic analyze all I did I loved it and what can be
coming back...achievements...I love while so much when it came out like microchip is ions
...stuff all the time and exchanges for things in the real-world right and now
we don't have time to demo that maybe if you guys stick around after this but this is the native
...that...that...giving out for the kits the idea is that
has very polished experience very native experience but you know, for the head of the family for the head of the
clanor the tribe with built a summer informs application which is
mostly...the desktop right the head of general probably have a desktop and,
...will have android and idealize but we didn't really want to spent...much...wide that's what you
build and it's and...for managing your child's relationships...you know,
when joey gets a little bit starts to good...and start to get but ideas...you know, I'd like a
...you get around the edges, you know, kind of relationship you're in there and,
you get the monitor the communication say maybe not maybe not
...play with this yet so we'll show you the app later on
...solution...look at this is a proper now let us show you how we build this how abilities
popping and I think...to switch to the...hamburger what where there's like
a no,...nothing like...take a look at the solution really quick so
...I have my analysis of accounts of an android ios my watch
...application...shared server code as well?
So, we can actually see a lot going on over...scroll down here all my view
...so each page of the applications as an vm became...talk
how many of you familiar with ibm but if you're not just like nbc?
More...more...
Or now but the idea the following idea the idea...I learned it wellthe idea of the
ibm model is that you splinter application in the part that
...the stores the information that's typically the model and on the other end of
the spectrum the platform specific bits the view right in the milieu have the
glued that bring this to worlds together the...model so it's a way of structuring your application
I've kind of fun to build this application because we would add a feature,
for example,...without a feature to android he would put
...model on his view and the next morning ...them that was working
...the I'll just pick it up and fill in and it was very nice to see how
...was being developed very rapidly and all of the
logical of the data mining and information was shared so the ui when we have
to the...of the average piece we just had to why...the you why
that's very interesting I remember getting on the slack in the morning and have a conversation...and,
is overseas and I said...going to...this page I
said don't worry although logics done call this one method everything's...link to parent
you're done uploading a photo all handled automatically in fact going into the
profile view models a actually really interesting we have different interface for
data management's actually storing things in a local sequel light database
with public gathers and...some this causal and very familiar to you are using and, things in here but
...actually pull down into some of these methods
for instance let me go ahead and say pick photo for here...the
logic for picking and uploading the actual photo and taking the
photos all in shared code?
Since...developers we can abstract away all the hard bits of ios...android and
create a common interface to say take a photo asynchronous
...goes out to ios or android under the hood takes a photos picks
...photo...upload that to our server automatically going to worry about rain is
...ios or android bits handle...clean maintain
...set of code all here as well which is really amazing
and then of course we're building out the user interfaces inside a visual studio...our
story board designers you can see it is pretty, pretty nicely laid out very large we can
dive in when you go in you can actually come in and modify any of the properties
...dive into this page for instance...one-to-one.
Come in
...like different properties ad different buttons and widgets and modify the toolbar of a full
...here on the right-hand side so I can drag-and-drop any of the different controls into
the views we can see how we kind of...this out some of the pages...more manual code behind
...we can see here the different cells that were creating and filling in the ui
...the code behind of course the same thing is true for android application but instead of using a story
board we have android xml files which are very much like
xhtml files but just without data mining...very much the same we
...our first ...login pager actual or signing up to is an email
...nickname we can flipping we can drag different items around on here so if I
wanted...another button the search for button drag it down to get guidelines and
...what that's doing behind the hood is generating all the android xml for me to
actually get this here...I really love about the structure this code is that
in the code behind for instance if I diamond let's say my profile
fragment there's really not that much code what I'm doing here is I'm just having a
little, little...whenever I click the avatar I just call-in and say would you like to pick a photo
...a photo and I call out to my view model...a photo take a photo and the rest is
handle format automatically most of it is just setting up the user interface and
we can see here down the bottom...property change notifications so whenever I
...avatar get notified...react to the ui...it is busy so I'm updating
uploading something just react to that natively so the
bulk shared code is now automatically scaled...a bug
in one product you simply fix it righted unit tests around it and now it's
good to go and I think there's a couple of interesting things we also built
that consul version so we could test
...easily from the consul for unix...we do like that we also have here the watch
get application so that's the one that just show you a second ago
...the storyboards you want I don't know where...get and,...
And, the last the last row there at the end is...is...we're sharing with the server which we have a
separate solution because we're developing in parallel but, that's where all the shared coded so this is the
story work for the apple watch ...just...you tap n and then you can navigate through
get your entire message log and then also here the different tasks titles that are coming
in so broccoli ...need your homework that sort of thing,
yeah, and, the server codes the server code is here as well and we see down here we have the apple watch
kids but also the server client...the shared code and that shared across everything
we know when you go in and you look at what we're using and I actually look at my references I think this is what's
really interesting and is go to manage new get packages and then I just go to install packages
...high-wage many packages its new get package...
You get...google new get.
All right so that was.
Good all-new get.
When I love about visual studio is at loads relatively pretty quick?
There we go there we go areas...
...I dropped out my...risk it no not just show the reference we have them there zoom
...help you so you are using all of the android support libraries down here google
place services for cloud messaging or using a bunch of my libraries I wrote
furs cross-platform settings and the slider tabs...button
sequel light or using different media plugins google klout messaging
System xml validation web for
sockets or using all of these amazing libraries that are out there in a dot net ecosystem
that we can take in...crypto which was various cross-platform that's the one point
...actually by erin are not I believe from microsoft as a cross-platform.
Crypto library...uses the native ios
...android cryptography.
Systems be lightning quick to do all the encryption...in fact we had a couple of slides about the whole
crypto thing but when we looked at this slide it was just boxes and errors and more boxes
and like we can show this stuff is just the to boring but,
it's actually a fascinating problem to solve a how to make ...to
...your communication say it's a little more complicated than just all we have a public keep turns out that
you get some patting and get some forward secrecy and interesting stuff so is there anything else
...to show from the solution they...get...now all right let's
...each macro lines and ...have my ...got here?
So, we did that...is now we talked about the...boarding and.
And, the reason why we wanted to
...some easier awarding was because was for a couple of reasons first...
done remember password second we can we couldn't use twitter facebook because you know,
...and five-year also technically not eligible to get account from these networks so,
...system...simple and what we did is we
...that we used...on the mac and adjective send the as messages for...
your phone-number or email addresses the...send grid from the adders store and
...email automatically send that out the same thing is if I invite
...signed up you actually get a notifications on boarding and...your friends became very...
there as well and, I think we touched on this let me let me just yeah,
we did we did touch on this I kind of messed of the flows sorry about that
but, I think that what is important to remember here what is important to remember here that every minute
that your child spends on kinder chat is a minute let you have to worry about your
kid using another
another channel application that is not monitored and also not every mom has a
datacenter to cracked the strong cryptography used by other systems so,
even if you wanted to sometimes might be out of your budget so this really I think that
we're really delivering here a lot of value for families that want to keep an eye on what's going on there
and I was interesting to go back to that last great earthquake is that gamification in this
actually happened relatively quick gaussian vision game...find this really quick was one-oh-one
...we...yes so we had to be able to prototype extremely fast
are user interface right so we came up with this beautiful, beautiful...and we started play around a master
...the number what happens when the...millions of points...trade things that we needed
away that easily prototype right as well which is very interesting so this is where
the cycle of build compile debug got a little bit annoying
so we actually gave it a shot and you component examine the...introducing today
...arming inspector and...inspector is it's similar to the
...or firefox are ip tools where you're able to inspect the live up right
you're able to issues some...csharp commands or f sharp
...against the running app you get to get you get to inspect the internal state
of the application very much like you do on the browser, browser this works on...works
...windows and works on works and...they can do it for angry can do it for ios
can be for wpf applications and
...applications because we couldn't get vm were running with the
and regular the same time we're going to do these them on mac so, let's show that?
And, I've never done these life so, we'll see how these goes so,
this is out...you see here on the left...inspector of already
launcher have the application running on the left and...is really this interactive
shelter csharp is using...still not using roslyn we're using the same
...that we had for a while and you know, you can issue a very simple commands like two-plus
two what is interesting about this and this is you know,...the...
this is just csharp...plane csharp here...line.
Hello.
I actually missy...do this gal.
Let me see what happens if I do this csharp six hello.
Works although it's pretty nice that's nice surprise.
But, let me show you this is actually running in process what.
...reopen.
Relaunch the simulator maybe...this...
Well, and, now you can see how the application can fail.
What happened to this thing so go?
Trickle-down view viel
...this one window scale.
Seventy-five there we go all right so I
...inspector again and now let me attached to this process, you know,
what I might have been debugging I might have been actually inspecting the app itself
so, images resize this...the...I just want to not have to do this in front of you it's a
little bit embarrassing anyway let me see using...
All...process.
So, using system io you've seen this before
so I think that we have a couple of nice the features here because this is not really running
...its own communicating with a target process actually running inside the application so,
for example, I can say directory wvu dot get files...pi place
...a little...for my convenience so I'm going to.
I'm going to loader file...dot from...
...veggie...live-in...and the
we load the imagine we have a special...can load the image you can also use other elements that you
...red and will always...collars right...it
right there in the ui let me load again the image but assigning to a variable?
...around and similar to what you do with.
Similar to what you do.
What...web inspector you can also use...bottom here to select one of the elements in
the ui so I'm going to select...little guy and it already...assigned that when you click
...the images...are variable selected view...I can explore some of the properties on that thing,
for example, the frame...to tell me
...the position right now I can say selected view?
And, I know that say image view I can say
the e match can be the broadly so now I can change the broccoli life.
Thank you thank you thank you.
Let me show you a little bit ...limit different this actually shows one of the problems that
we had here so we have these label here it's overloading chopped we have a little...there so
...like this thing but the problem that this is actually...view made about
ton of other little things so when I tried selected such little bit obnoxious...it's a...
so what I'm going to do is I'm going to go here I'm going to fetch a three-d view of the.
So, I'm going to like the view that I one...that you can see how it's getting composer I'm going to select that
...and now selected...I'm going to say what is that well
...it's a is what I want?
...I don't think that's one let me get this poppy I think it's
the little guy ok let me go there and it's a label so I can say
I think that it's a large number right so one of the things that I could do is now, for example,
could should...I could just said this like adjust font-size to fit with...
and ios property this is not something I did for them is just...as property and,
that's affecting the box they can go customize it see what's wrong and,
in fact I could just have done that directly from here right I could have just selected
...element and it's a little difficult now that I have that I don't have a big display
here to play with but you can just go here and see what the properties are what is going on with your
compare with your component right so?
...go back so like that because I think...selected something else now
let me so like the this little guy here and.
And, now we can go back.
...can see that this is a problem again right might text nys being left the
...so I can just right here text alignment people
ui text align mend dot center.
And, there goes so all of these are actually
ios property is running on the target process so you can explore all the properties change
...properties say what is going on we're adding support for monitoring network
...and other things as extra taps and,
it's we're going to make it available as a new get a as a new j
...so that so, that you can actually very easily added
to any application so the distribution of the software will be a new j that you can
...the knows that comes with the app you can run it and then and,
you can start inspecting now the other thing I just wanted to do because I'm trying to send
a subliminal message to my daughter.
Is I want pick this collection view here so let me see selected
That background...what I want I want...background color and we pick maybe.
Maybe this one so what we have here.
Selected view.
Background color so I can say you...from
And, now I have some broccoli on the background not very
...I thought that ...I could do that if you're...some points so.
So, let's go back to...slides so,
that's our summer inspector and you'll be able to able to use it to
do under ios and both windows and mac as well as wpf and more
The next challenges right so we got a great application and now we
...to deliver a great experience everywhere right we want-to make sure that our kids get the
best experience possible and, that's the other apple watch just-in-time because they
set up until three again can get there can get everything running so?
We've been shown at all on really...devices...pop in...the
...six lots of on six-plus naturally gotta have it was interesting is
when I was a kid uniting get the latest and greatest technology at all now is wanted it but I was
in a way a little bit...coming...kind of
trickle-down a little bit right and what happens is this right when you look at the android market and,
we know that...fragmentation...problem but when you look at the...market we got
these dating from google a couple of nights ago but this is roughly
what the market is for parents right we got a bunch of people
...got some people in jelly bean ice cream sanded...for you and...
we're thinking about parents this is okay but the reality is that
the is that kids don't really...really get the latest device right
...a new device comes out this is roughly what happens?
Right.
The one percent of the children of the one percent we'll certainly get the five percent
the five a lowly bob but what happens is that the...basically give
...all devices to your children right so you end up with this so,
you end up with...where it's actually very important support things like gingerbread or ice cream sandwich
...be all devices but and I'm not giving you know, my two-year-old toddler a
...six-plus I'm going to give him the iphone three-g as that is still running around
the house and this is actually a challenge for us as developers
because I had the latest and greatest phones myself when I was testing kinder chat
for the very personas on my modal...sidekick caddo assessing and lollipops
...all the different lawyer the lollipops design with material design
...very excited about it...we actually started getting...a
...active finding out that there...some issues on-the-field how to create a dedicated
...the user interface...sure that what we wanted to have
happened was actually happening in apps and scaling and all these different devices
...know what different devices these kids would be running so that's
why we actually have an entire product that we mention a little bit earlier
...task cloud
...we writing automated user interface scripts all in csharp other visual
studios...studio out automate are user interface so when I log
...my login process work what happens when...email others don't entering
email address is the ui reacting but then also take those tests run it locally
...a simulator or shipments the
...has hundred upon thousands...devices for ios
an android social media show this year so which machining do not were...some?
So, I'm over here on salmon studio you can just in visual
...well and I still have my entire application we can see here
all ios android the same solutions same projects open both visual studios eras
...now I have a kinder chat test project insists and unit of
your familiar with any of the units assessing frameworks here we built on top and unit but we created
...ui tasks so insider with a package them and ui...and,
unit so that...start and test the sign up
flow so unsightly here...I can take screen shots along
away but the way of selecting visual elements that are displayed not
just by pixels of x and y but actually the identifiers that
were displaying so we have here for being able to enter
taxed querying different buttons are they letting ahead back...what's happening here is...this unit
that using and api that will communicate with the remote process and
...sure that certain things are taking place so...to make sure that the app wrongs and it's a unit that is
the actually testing the behavior of the...life is not really
...testing like those you know, two-plus...to...actually testing with how can
...already have your business logic tasks already this is the user interface...can
...happening on the server...me just go over here my test...actually just run this task
...the sign up process...to make sure that I want to be able to successfully sign up here
...not touching anything stand back museum answering tax back and forth inside here
we see the button enabler disable with my rejects that I have answering different
...and continuing on.
...we saw the entire user interface change just right insider there and that's all done
encode additionally we tested another one for doing messages so what happens now after the
sign up process but I also want to send messages here we go we test that flow again.
We have tools built right into
actionable live interactive ripples you can actually build-out your tasks.
And, then copy them right into visual...here again is open up talking
...betsy's...guy like...there we go.
Back and forth pose interesting
...I'm running them locally on a simulator which means I can smoke test any of my
...right here however what happens when actually want to do more
...so I've done my
...and what you can do now...these tasks simply load them up to the same
and task cloud here's all the different devices you can go in...see all the different device ios
kick at jelly bean etc we took that same task those running local we
...kinder chat for android right here in this...task cloud...a few different tasks
...we actually found some very glaring issues we ran for different
tasks for changing friends passwords switching we see that we have a task that's failing on
ten different devices what was actually...is that when we started this things that...so choked
as club...to find a way of making these fail we actually have to do that because
...road that's when it turns out that we did have a failure and
natural failure so this is we're going to show you a natural fehler that occurred when we're building it
exactly so here is the application running on here this is a successful romy you can see
...running on eighty plus different devices and go into any single device get a
full screenshot snapshot of it so I can upload that later get
council logs along the way of anything that's happening on...device...go back
so here for instance I could actually just navigate down and I get updates
...every step that happened the same steps that you saw happening locally you can see them
...execute and all these devices but this one was interesting we actually ran into a few
issues right off the bat with actually just smaller really form factors are trying to open the
...but here for instance I login I'm so like the user
and this all seems good I send a message the message was sent so we can see
actually on the...side over here I...make sure that I can go back to the main messaging
page so in this command I'm actually taping this button right here the back button or the up
arrow if you will so when I taped that we can see that are actually fails?
On all these top row devices what's really intriguing is that
it was failing to go back on all of our ice cream sandwich devices I
...some bad functionality and api that didn't exist and it was crashing the
application they couldn't continue on now the rest of the devices that were successful to
go through that step go here and now I can diamond get more information about
the specific tasks failures what was going on obviously here there's nothing there but we can see that
...go back groups skips the one of these.
Was failing and get the snapshot I can see the test failures that
were going on as well here.
Is really powerful and this is...actually solve that problem this which a little bit
...logic as well so that's the our of
writing user interface scripts user interface ship into the task that has
on devices but then we actually shipped...right we actually
...chandra first beta thing we were crying and monday and
...started
...problems...and we sort of capturing those so we're using them
and insights which is a lot it's a framework that allows you to log exceptions
...exceptions errors or send analytics about what's happening
your application so what we had originally added things for the sake of examining what was
happening with the application we also got caption all the crashes so we're going to show you how
...capture here and let me actually show you how easy it was
set up and running so inside of my main application added a new get packages all this new
...so here...have an initialize...android application same thing over here
...and insights and then my shared code is a portable class
library so everything up inside of my share library high
divx indy here and go to my helpers?
Services there we go I have a longer utility pyro some of
these that I track report different exceptions I can even
...time so...interesting here is that we got connection we have
our dashboard and this is interesting we see something horrible
happened here about seven eight thousand warnings and
...crashes and what's interesting is energy
see crashes report over time so these are session
...of how many sessions are occurring in the application compared to the crashes so this
actually pretty good...early development crashes and we...things early on we got a lot
of users in but we had a lot of warnings...reporting as well
...actually going to mike how we can see that I'm actually just have a bunch of...exceptions because
...server went down a full stack trace of a rich stack trace like a message our trying to send
a message was linear all my different device information this was happening on
...for instance but let me go into this is rash and this
crashes what happened yesterday right,
...were crying and one of these personal...means
...has its own set of measure machines we have a bunch of those but it
...that we just had started developing...form personal accounts so we run
out of credit on that one so this crashes are actually was running out of credit on the as
...machines exactly what...really...how...was...forgot some different
so has some debug in there that was actually setting some different properties so when I went
to production actually for...to take those flags out I got...we see here I fixed...push
...new version and some people didn't update so blame them
...come in and say that this is close and...reports back additionally here
we can see all the different users that are coming...as all anonymous data that's coming and we can track the
different sessions that are occurring in the applications starting the
arguments the different messages that are coming back from the server and...sort...here
now what we're doing here what is important is that you can see...application starts and when it gets sent
to the background and resume essentially have a history of what happened with your application as yet
insights the application you can see what was the workflow that might have led to
a crash or might have led to a particular condition in the application exactly right it's a
...a it's a little it helps you with the archaeology of a bug of course we
...some different events so here we can see the average time for uploading avatars you should
parallelism into...into this right here?
...so actually get nice daily events back and forth ascending messages how often
...people sending messages we can see that...lot...here and then the
servers went down and I was no good and then we came back up and you can really see this is, you know,
this is exactly when we put it in just over a little week ago...having
...here as well so how long did it take to actually save a profile back to the server
upload...photo or search for a friend inside
...one was the last time it occured this is really important because if I introduce new app
logic into here that was searching for a friend and actually broke
...cn when I push...new update now everything's taking longer something go back and...that we saw
some interesting things is what you...different statistics
avenir as well as you can add additional attribute such as maybe popular user names the avatars you
select different themes right now and I in fact I think with the theme we figure out...the beginning which
...label that said pinker blow at what we immediately discover is that
are toddler audience was not ready to read pinker blue so once we change that
...or blue collars it became very obvious very simple the to pick-up
exactly,
exactly so you see this shift overtime and actually using this analytics to improve the
application at the same time getting the manage and native crash reports...that single-line
...code you have just initialize you get all your manage and native crashes right there,
yeah, I think the other piece that we learned that ponders can really use a messaging application
of the result was on distinguishable from the encrypted version
...so we gotta go we're going
...that assumptions of course you have all the other analytics you expect app versions
different os variations you can see which ones are actually important here as well
...something interesting we saw yesterday which was these to have it here when we started low testing
...on...we want to load...the application...as a servers you can see
up this big increase because or using...denmark datacenter so,
that's what you see that spiked that's...can...that's or datacenter there.
Go back to...so let's...I think we're going to wrap this up how much that we have left where
...so, what was it,
yeah, so, it was really interesting is that so now we we're getting ready...finishing the slide
deck and I think was always...me when I shut my very first applications my boss can is that
while great...we have iowa's andrew windows but what's the share code
that your sharing with the maintain ability and this so I told me...last night and I can run the
stats no big deal have the little app...does it and we actually got our code sharing
...for this application again built in two weeks between a few
...about fifty percent code across all platforms and ios and seventy percent of
android what early interesting again with that client-server relationship
...twenty percent of the happen the server and the client...shared
...a share that gray right there is a shared layer across all of our applications and
ios one is a little bit because we spend a lot more time...a lot of...animations and...a lot of different things
we're adding more platform specific things that we can abstract away later on it gets even higher?
So, now of course that's
some of the statistics but I'm sure you guys want to learn exactly how to get started obviously that is
...dot com download...free trial get up and running if you have an already what you'll should of course
...university which I hinted at a little bit before so everything here what's interesting is
...universes I actually examine university
classes mobiles moving so fast new operating systems android where
a apple watch new versions I wasn't android coming out all the
time zimmer university enables you to get up and running maybe not knowing anything a
...ios or android a...out live interactive instructors become a fully
sam examines certified developer zebra dot com slash university.
Anyone has any questions feel free will be here.